<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-01-02T00:57:08-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">jjkcharles.github.io</title><entry><title type="html">Hello (again) World!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/self/2023/01/01/hello.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello (again) World!" /><published>2023-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/self/2023/01/01/hello</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/self/2023/01/01/hello.html">&lt;p&gt;I have been blogging since 2008 and been maintaining my own personal site since around the same timeframe - but, those were also the days I wasn&apos;t unaware of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Version_control&quot; title=&quot;version control&quot;&gt;version control&lt;/a&gt;. Couple it with the fact that I was using free hosting options (PHP/MySql) and that I haven&apos;t tended to my site/blog for ~2 years - I ended up losing lots of my blog content due to several service shutdowns and me not paying attention to the deadline offered by those compaines to get my backup done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;This happened&lt;/del&gt; I became aware of this around 2016, and at that point any attempts I made at recovering the lost data went in vain. This eventually led me to losing interest in blogging. While I was unleashing the technical writer within me in the last 5+ years to produce Work related technical documents which is well received (so far) within my org., it quite didn&apos;t get me to the same level of engagement (though limited) nor the diverse topics I get to explore through my blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been contemplating setting up a blog for myself since last year, but haven&apos;t invested the time in doing so. Now that I got a little break from work, took this as an opportunity to setup a quick &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot; title=&quot;Jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; site which I am planning to host at least to beging with using &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot; title=&quot;Github Pages&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hoping to blog more in the coming days/weeks/months/years. Wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if I am not able to solve problems of the world, I can at the least &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hanselman.com/blog/your-words-are-wasted&quot; title=&quot;own my words&quot;&gt;own my words&lt;/a&gt;, create a knowledge repository for my future self to look back into and may be as a side-effect help someone else as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jjk_charles</name></author><category term="self" /><category term="blog" /><category term="self" /><summary type="html">I have been blogging since 2008 and been maintaining my own personal site since around the same timeframe - but, those were also the days I wasn&apos;t unaware of version control. Couple it with the fact that I was using free hosting options (PHP/MySql) and that I haven&apos;t tended to my site/blog for ~2 years - I ended up losing lots of my blog content due to several service shutdowns and me not paying attention to the deadline offered by those compaines to get my backup done.</summary></entry></feed>